Finding Aid for Stanford R. Ovshinsky papers
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Visual Materials
  - Machines (Box 87)
    - PV cell continuous roll-to-roll tandem processor, August 1982 (Box 81)
      (1st commercial, shipped to Sharp-ECD, Inc.)
    - PV continuous roll-to-roll, undated (Box 81)
      (3rd generation, under construction)
    - PV cell processor, 2nd generation multi-chamber research scale shipped to Sharp-ECD, Inc., August 1982 (Box 81)
      (1st generation shipped 1980)
    - PV large area PIN processor modules, June 1980 (Box 81)
    - PV processor-sequential stationary deposition, undated (Box 81)
    - PV transparent electrode processor, undated (Box 81)
    - PV TRAIN machine, November 1986 (Box 81)
      (Plant 2)
    - Vacuum deposition machine, undated (Box 81)
  - Maeda lunch and reception, May 17, 1984 (Box 81)
  - Magnet ball controls -- switches, relays, proximity and limit switches, undated (Box 81)
  - Melt spinning, 1985-1986 (Box 81)
  - Mexico, undated (Box 81)
  - Microelectronics -- memory, undated (Box 81)
  - Miscellaneous, undated; 4 folders (Box 81)
  - Miscellaneous negatives, undated (Box 81)
  - Miscellaneous -- solar, undated (Box 81)
  - Models
    - Builders, undated (Box 81)
    - Conformational changes without bond breaking, undated (Box 81)
    - Threshold switching and memory, September 1984 (Box 81)
  - Oxide, undated (Box 81)
  - People
    - Adler, David, 1983 (Box 81)
    - Acquaintances, friends, and family, 1963-? (Box 81)
    - Bacon, Nancy, undated (Box 81)
    - Birkenstock, James W., undated (Box 81)
    - Canella, Vin, undated (Box 81)
    - Chen, J.T., undated (Box 81)
    - Cohen, Morrel H., undated (Box 81)
    - Consultants, undated (Box 81)
    - Conway, Jack, undated (Box 81)
    - Cummings, Richard H., undated (Box 81)
    - Czubatyj, Wally, undated (Box 81)
    - De Neufville, John, undated (Box 81)
    - ECD -- Wright, Neal, Nelson, Flemming, Fogen, Sie, Helbers, March 1969 (Box 81)
    - ECD personnel, undated; 2 folders (Box 81)
    - Ervin, Christine, January 1994 (Box 81)
      (Stan Ovshinsky with Christine at US Department of Energy news conference)
    - Flasck, Dick, undated (Box 81)
    - Goldstein, Alex, 1988 (Box 81)
    - Guha, Subhendu, undated (Box 81)
    - Hack, Michael, undated (Box 81)
    - Hanak, Joe, undated (Box 81)
    - Harwood, Julius, undated (Box 81)
      (President of Ovonic Synthetic Material Co.)
    - Himelfarb, Alan M., undated (Box 81)
      (President and COO of EV Global Motors)
    - Hudgens, Stephen, undated (Box 81)
      (Vice-President of Research and Development at ECD)
    - Iris Ovshinsky, undated (Box 81)
    - Iris Ovshinsky, Klose, and Chang, undated (Box 81)
    - Ito, Momoko, undated (Box 81)
    - Izu, Masa, undated (Box 81)
    - Johnson, Robert, undated (Box 81)
    - Kvant with Gorbachev, undated (Box 81)
    - Keem, John, undated (Box 81)
    - Leach, Robert, undated (Box 81)
    - Livesay, Alastar, 2001 (Box 81)
    - Mahr, Sam and Brenda Walton, undated (Box 81)
    - Marquart, undated (Box 81)
    - Metzger, James, undated (Box 81)
    - Miscellaneous, undated; 2 folders (Box 81)
    - Nadorov, Ovshinsky, Leach, and others -- KVANT, April 26, 1990 (Box 81)
    - Ohta, Ted, 2003 (Box 81)
    - Mott, Sir Nevill
      - Institute lecture, April 28, 1986 (Box 81)
      - Signing book, undated (Box 81)
    - O'Leary, Hazel, undated (Box 81)
    - Powell, Max, undated (Box 81)
    - Pryor, Roger, undated (Box 81)
    - Rabi, Isidor, undated (Box 81)
    - Rabi, Isidor, undated (Box 110)
    - Reischauer, Edwin, undated (Box 110)
    - Schaeffer, Isaac, undated (Box 110)
    - Seder, Art, undated (Box 110)
    - Silver, Marvin, undated (Box 110)
      (Co-author of Disordered Materials)
    - Stan Ovshinsky's parents-Ben and Bertha, undated (Box 110)
    - Stempel, Robert, undated (Box 110)
    - Synes, Stanley, undated (Box 110)
    - Tech and production brochure, 1999; 2 folders (Box 110)
    - Trebilcott, James, undated (Box 110)
    - Vining, Richard A., undated (Box 110)
    - Rosa Ovshinsky, December 2008 (Box 110)
      (Cambodia)
  - Products
    - Auto show and racing, 1990-1995 (Box 110)
    - Battery
      - Batteries, 1989-2000(?) (Box 110)
      - Electric scooters, undated (Box 110)
      - Electric vehicles, 1993-1995(?) (Box 110)
      - GM
        - Impact -- car, 1994 (Box 110)
        - Ovonic II -- cell and family of batteries, undated (Box 110)
        - Ovonic module, 1998 (Box 110)
          (used for 1998 Detroit Auto Show)
      - Honda, undated (Box 110)
      - Manufacturing process, undated (Box 110)
      - NiMH licensees, 1994 (Box 110)
    - Coatings
      - Coated vs. uncoated, undated (Box 110)
      - Drills, March 1983(?) (Box 110)
      - Southwall PECVD production machine, January 2000 (Box 83)
        (high-speed microwave)
      - Tool applications, undated (Box 83)
      - Transparent plastic, undated (Box 83)
        (glass hard surface)
    - EAROM (Electronically alterable read-only memory) array, bit, 1024 (Box 83)
      (negatives)
    - Electronic Info. Processor, undated (Box 83)
      (with Gazaleh)
    - Electrophotography
      - 1985(?) (Box 83)
      - Canon machine, April 1986 (Box 83)
        (Plant 16)
      - Test piece -- Canon, May 1986 (Box 83)
    - Film
      - Microfilm, undated (Box 83)
      - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 83)
      - Non-silver photo duplication, undated (Box 83)
        (TEBAC with Wozie?)
    - Hydrogen
      - Car, March 1999(?) (Box 83)
      - Corrosion testing, undated (Box 83)
      - Energy system process, undated (Box 83)
      - Engine, undated (Box 83)
      - Engine demo, undated (Box 83)
      - Fuel cell, undated (Box 83)
      - Heat pump, undated (Box 83)
    - Microvonic File, 1981-1985 (Box 83)
      (with Freya Saito)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 83)
    - N-Gen
      - Microelectronics cleanroom, 1985 (Box 83)
        (computer project, with Roger Pryor)
      - Smart card, undated (Box 83)
    - Old ECD, undated (Box 83)
    - Optical Memory
      - EEPROM, undated (Box 83)
      - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 83)
      - Toray phasewriter, undated (Box 83)
    - Ovonic Design Systems -- touch sensitive input, undated (Box 83)
    - Ovonic Imaging Systems
      - 2D imager, undated (Box 83)
      - Data encoding bar, undated (Box 83)
      - Factory of the future, undated (Box 83)
      - Flat panel display, 1986-1987(?) (Box 83)
      - Laptop, 1988 (Box 83)
      - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 83)
      - Office automation, undated (Box 83)
      - Ovonic imager, undated (Box 83)
    - Oxygen sensors for exhaust system, undated (Box 83)
    - Quartet white copyboard and linear array scanner, undated (Box 83)
    - RMM, undated (Box 83)
    - Scanning Electron Microscope (SEM), undated (Box 83)
    - Solar
      - Amorphous vs. crystalline -- bullet, undated (Box 83)
      - Calculator, undated (Box 83)
      - Car rooftop, 1986(?) (Box 83)
      - Cells, 1984(?) (Box 83)
      - Continuous roll, undated (Box 83)
      - Crystalline cells, undated (Box 84)
      - Crystalline cells-ARCO, undated (Box 84)
      - Crystalline cells to Japan, August 1984 (Box 84)
      - Solar electric module, undated (Box 84)
      - Electric vehicle charging station, undated (Box 84)
      - Equipment, undated (Box 84)
      - Fishing buoy -- Nippon Steel, undated (Box 84)
      - Flexible cell with bullet hole and broken glass cell, undated (Box 84)
      - Hawaii, 1989-1990(?) (Box 84)
      - India, 1991(?) (Box 84)
      - ITO machine, January 1985 (Box 84)
      - Lamp posts, undated (Box 84)
      - Machines
        - Metalizer, undated (Box 84)
        - Miscellaneous, undated; 3 folders (Box 84)
      - Manufacturing plant -- 1000 sq. ft., undated (Box 84)
      - Marketing, undated (Box 84)
      - Mexico, undated (Box 84)
      - Miscellaneous, undated; 3 folders (Box 84)
      - Modules, 1986(?) (Box 84)
      - Ovation -- car, May-August, 1986 (Box 84)
      - Panels, undated (Box 84)
      - Panel mounting comparison, undated (Box 84)
      - Panels -- PV International, undated (Box 84)
      - Panels -- USSC roof shingles being packed go to Olympic village in Atlanta, 1996 (Box 84)
      - PV canon drum machine, undated (Box 84)
      - PV cell PCU 800, undated (Box 84)
      - Photovoltaic plant pilot -- ECD and ARCO joint development, undated (Box 84)
      - Photovoltaic processor
        - 1982-1984 (Box 84)
        - In production, undated (Box 84)
        - Under construction-Sovonics, undated (Box 84)
      - Photovoltaic production, undated (Box 84)
      - Pilot plant, 1981 (Box 85)
      - Roof shingle and fan, undated (Box 85)
      - Sovonics beach bag, undated (Box 85)
      - Spain-irrigation, 1986 (Box 85)
      - Sunpal
        - Battery, radio, August 1986 (Box 85)
        - Boat, RV, car, undated (Box 85)
        - Camping, beach, fishing, mountains, undated (Box 85)
      - Thin substrate, undated (Box 85)
        (with Joe Hanak)
      - Transparent electrode material, undated (Box 85)
      - Ultralight
        - MA series, 1987-1988 (Box 85)
        - Stan Ovshinsky, Joe Hanak, and Pat Dahlin, undated (Box 85)
        - United Solar, undated (Box 85)
      - Video camera, undated (Box 85)
      - Vietnam, 1995 (Box 85)
      - Warning flasher, undated (Box 85)
    - Thermoelectric, undated (Box 85)
    - Thermoelectric -- OTEG generator, 1981-1986(?) (Box 85)
    - Thermoelectric -- TE device with gasoline engine and wood stove, undated (Box 85)
    - X-ray optics
      - Clean room, June 1986 (Box 85)
      - Device elements and mirrors, undated (Box 85)
      - Phillips spectrometer, undated (Box 85)
      - Reflector, undated (Box 85)
  - Rapid solidification, undated (Box 85)
    (with Dick Clayton)
  - Russia
    - Delegation, April-May 1990 (Box 85)
    - Embassy -- scooter and Vice President Gore, 1997(?) (Box 85)
    - KVANT -- Moscow, January 1990 (Box 85)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 85)
  - Shareholders Meeting
    - 1992 (Box 85)
    - April 1995 (Box 85)
    - 1985-1986 (Box 85)
  - Shows
    - AFL-CIO Union Industries, May 1995 (Box 85)
    - Auto-Chicago, 1998 (Box 85)
    - Trade
      - Cobo Hall, undated (Box 85)
      - GM Ovonic battery display, undated (Box 85)
      - IEEE PV conference, 1984 (Box 85)
        (Sovonics)
      - National Hardware, 1985 (Box 85)
        (Chicago, Sovonics sunpak)
  - Smithsonian (Box 85)
    (Ovonic Tech Company chart, Ovshinsky's University of Michigan honorary degree)
  - Solar Corona eclipse, May 28, 1900 (Box 85)
  - Ovshinsky
    - 80th Birthday, 2002 (Box 85)
    - 70th Birthday photo album, 1992 (Box 87)
    - Contents of Ovshinsky's photo album, undated (Box 85)
    - Drawings, undated (Box 85)
    - Drawings -- Ovshinsky's Fans publication, 1982 (Box 85)
    - Fritzsche, Hellmut, undated (Box 85)
    - Machine shop, undated (Box 85)
    - Products (Box 85)
    - Oakland press, November 1985 (Box 85)
    - Leach, Ralph F., undated (Box 85)
      (Board member)
    - Madan, Aran, undated (Box 85)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 85)
    - Nagashima and Ovshinsky, undated (Box 110)
    - Products (Box 85)
      - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 85)
      - Optical disk, undated (Box 85)
      - Solar panel -- Japan, undated (Box 85)
    - Parks, Rosa Ovshinsky, undated (Box 85)
    - Promotional, undated; 2 folders (Box 86)
    - Publicity photos, 1992-2000 (Box 86)
    - Recent, 2005-2010 (Box 86)
      (2 CDs)
    - Rosa Ovshinsky, Dr. and Mrs. Ohta in Kyoto, July 2008 (Box 86)
    - Umene, Mr. and Mrs. --NSC, October 1985 (Box 86)
  - Stan and Iris Ovshinsky
    - Anniversary party -- surprise, 1984 (Box 86)
    - Bio photos, 2000 (Box 86)
    - Christmas and holiday cards, 1969-1985 (Box 86)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 86)
    - Miscellaneous photographs for Notre Dame book, undated; .ZIP file
    - Pauling, Linus, undated (Box 86)
    - Powell, Colin, 2000 (Box 86)
      (Troy, MI, Heroes of Chemistry)
    - Promotional, undated; 3 folders (Box 86)
    - Promotional with Stempel, February 3, 1998 (Box 86)
      (by Eric Smith)
    - Trips
      - Caracas, July 1982 (Box 86)
        (with R. Calloratti and Paul Gray of MIT)
      - China, September 1984 (Box 86)
      - Japan
        - August 1983(?) (Box 86)
        - February 1986 (Box 86)
        - Kobe conference, November 1984 (Box 86)
        - Kyoto Nobel lecture, June 1986 (Box 86)
        - Meeting with NTT, April 1985 (Box 86)
        - Samsung, March 1990; 2 volumes (Box 87)
        - YKK, January 1986 (Box 86)
        - Yoshida Kogyo K.K., January 1986 (Box 86)
      - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 86)
  - Stan and Rosa Ovshinsky -- UC Berkeley Review photo shoot, 2008 (Box 86)
    ( CD of photos)
  - Superconductivity -- Rosa Ovshinsky with Squid machine, undated (Box 86)
  - Switching, undated (Box 86)
  - Transistors, undated (Box 86)
- Lake Angelus Observatory
  The Lake Angelus Observatory series (0.4 linear feet; 1938-1980) consists of miscellaneous records from the Hulbert-McMath Observatory in Lake Angelus, Michigan. Included are photographs of the facility, a 1967 newsletter, and guest books containing signatures of visitors from 1938 through 1980.
  - Guest books, (3 books), 1938-1980 (Box 108)
  - Newsletter, 1967 (Box 108)
  - Photographs, circa, 1940 (Box 108)
Related material
Researchers interested in Michigan inventors and inventions, in applied physical sciences, and in technological development in the state, especially as it pertains to industry, may wish to consult the following collections held by the Bentley Historical Library:
Marston Bates papers
Clark J. Charnetski papers
Thomas M. Donahue papers
Industrial Development Division (University of Michigan) records
Inventors Council of Michigan records
Russell V. Judson papers
Eugene H. Leslie papers
Michigan Technology Council records
Arthur D. Moore papers
William Charles Parkinson papers
Keeve Milton Siegel papers
George Owen Squier papers
Robert C. Stempel papers
Thomas R. Stockton papers
Juris Upatnieks papers
Wallace C. Williams papers
Shien-Ming Wu papers
Chia-Shun Yih papers
Philip Newell Youtz papers
Also, papers of Stan Ovshinsky's son, Harvey Ovshinsky, Michigan writer, journalist, news broadcaster, radio host, television producer, creative consultant, teacher, and founder of The Fifth Estate, Detroit's first underground newspaper.